<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Razvan-Marian AVRAMESCU</title>
    <link>https://www.avramescu.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Razvan-Marian AVRAMESCU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.avramescu.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin&#39;s Diminishing Monthly Returns - A Decade Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/bitcoins-diminishing-monthly-returns-a-decade-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/bitcoins-diminishing-monthly-returns-a-decade-ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past 15 years, Bitcoin has repeated one of the most recognizable rhythms in modern finance — a &lt;strong&gt;4-year cycle&lt;/strong&gt; of expansion and retracement.&lt;br&gt;
The structure has remained consistent: &lt;strong&gt;three years of bull market&lt;/strong&gt;, followed by &lt;strong&gt;one year of correction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This visualization explores what could happen if that rhythm continues, but with &lt;strong&gt;diminishing monthly returns&lt;/strong&gt; as adoption and market maturity gradually slow the pace of growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Months In – Passing the Probation Period at Onapsis</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/three-months-in-passing-the-probation-period-at-onapsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/three-months-in-passing-the-probation-period-at-onapsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After years of freelancing in eCommerce and backend development, this summer I made a significant career shift: I joined &lt;strong&gt;Onapsis&lt;/strong&gt; as a &lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer III – Python&lt;/strong&gt;. Recently, I passed the three-month probation period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This milestone may look small from the outside, but for me it came with important lessons about &lt;strong&gt;transition, culture and growth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Fixed Ruby on Rails Hotwire Broadcast for Unpublished Comments to Show Pending Approval for Current User</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-fixed-ruby-on-rails-hotwire-broadcast-for-unpublished-comments-to-show-pending-approval-for-current-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-fixed-ruby-on-rails-hotwire-broadcast-for-unpublished-comments-to-show-pending-approval-for-current-user/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my recent project, I faced a challenge with broadcasting comments in a Ruby on Rails application using Hotwire. The goal was to ensure that unpublished comments would only be visible to the user who created them, while published comments would be visible to everyone. Here’s how I tackled this issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Ended Up Choosing the Ford Kuga Over the RAV4 in Romania And Why It Was the Best Value SUV</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-ended-up-choosing-the-ford-kuga-over-the-rav4-in-romania-and-why-it-was-the-best-value-suv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-ended-up-choosing-the-ford-kuga-over-the-rav4-in-romania-and-why-it-was-the-best-value-suv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 160+ hours of research, during which Japanese brands consistently topped the list, I unexpectedly chose an American SUV: the Ford Kuga. Here’s how it outclassed the competition, including the beloved Toyota RAV4, in the Romanian market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English edition of my first children&#39;s book is now live on Amazon Kindle: Sophia and the Adventure of the Magic Block!</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/the-english-edition-of-my-first-childrens-book-is-now-live-on-amazon-kindle-sophia-and-the-adventure-of-the-magic-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/the-english-edition-of-my-first-childrens-book-is-now-live-on-amazon-kindle-sophia-and-the-adventure-of-the-magic-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most kids&#39; books don’t teach anything about money, let alone decentralized systems like Bitcoin. Mine does and it is finally available in English on Amazon Kindle: &lt;em&gt;Sophia and the Adventure of the Magic Block&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Generate Custom OpenGraph Images During Rails Deploys With Python and Ansible</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-generate-custom-opengraph-images-during-rails-deploys-with-python-and-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/how-i-generate-custom-opengraph-images-during-rails-deploys-with-python-and-ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most Rails apps do not bother with a custom OpenGraph image. Mine do and they are generated automatically during deployment using Python, Cairo and Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Walked Away From Magento After 10 Years</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/why-i-walked-away-from-magento-after-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/why-i-walked-away-from-magento-after-10-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over a decade working with Magento, I decided to walk away - not because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it anymore, but because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I was doing it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin - The Ultimate Manifestation of Satyagraha</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/bitcoin-the-ultimate-manifestation-of-satyagraha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/bitcoin-the-ultimate-manifestation-of-satyagraha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where financial systems often prioritize control and centralization, &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/strong&gt; embodies the spirit of &lt;strong&gt;Satyagraha&lt;/strong&gt; - truth-force and nonviolent resistance. Just as &lt;strong&gt;Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt; championed the power of peaceful protest to challenge injustice, Bitcoin empowers individuals to reclaim their financial sovereignty without firing a single shot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Nostr Login to My Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/adding-nostr-login-to-my-rails-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/adding-nostr-login-to-my-rails-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I will walk you through the process of integrating Nostr login functionality into my Rails application using the Nos2x extension. This involved modifying the Devise User model, adding a new route to handle Nostr users, and integrating JavaScript to enhance the login experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing &#34;In Archives&#34; Rails Applications Search Functionality</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/enhancing-in-archives-rails-applications-search-functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/enhancing-in-archives-rails-applications-search-functionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In web development, an efficient and user-friendly search function is essential for a good user experience. While working on the &amp;ldquo;In Archives&amp;rdquo; project, I initially cached the dataset without pagination, which led to poor performance—eight times worse than expected—because pagination was applied to the entire cached dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stack as a Magento Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/my-stack-as-a-magento-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/my-stack-as-a-magento-developer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a Magento developer, having the right tools and technologies at your disposal is crucial for efficient development and deployment. Here’s a look at the stack I use to streamline my workflow and enhance productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magekube is Back in Business - Your Magento Expert Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/magekube-is-back-in-business-your-magento-expert-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/magekube-is-back-in-business-your-magento-expert-is-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce that &lt;strong&gt;Magekube&lt;/strong&gt; is back in business! After a brief hiatus, I am reopening the doors and ready to provide the same expert Magento services that you have come to know and trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WooCommerce vs Magento - What’s Better for Your Business in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/woocommerce-vs-magento-whats-better-for-your-business-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/woocommerce-vs-magento-whats-better-for-your-business-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WooCommerce&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt; proudly stand as two of the most popular e-commerce solutions that power jointly nearly 40% of all e-stores on the web. While both have their strengths and weaknesses, it becomes quite challenging for a merchant to choose the best one amongst the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is aimed to help you give the answer to an ultimate question: &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s better for your business?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working on remote server locally</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/working-on-remote-server-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/working-on-remote-server-locally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This could sound weird, but should be strong as &lt;em&gt;think global, act local&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;work on remote server&lt;/strong&gt;, locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many programmers are using Mac, while some other developers are taking advantages of Linux latest technologies (such as Docker). Other people are just so old school, they still using the Microsoft and we have to respect that, if that works (and it should actually).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Magento 2017 Romania</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/meet-magento-2017-romania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/meet-magento-2017-romania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I was excited and honoured to have a workshop at Meet Magento 2017 Romania on October 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the arrival, the venue Grand Hotel Italia was great and we were very warm welcome, especially after a longer flight time because of the weather conditions (more precisely the airport was closed due to an intense fog and the airplane had to make circles in the air for about one hour).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organisers did a really great job and they switched my speech. Ben Marks cooled me down with a bottle of water, which proved more than useful for my emotions which I usually have when I present in public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first speech – Meet Magento 2017 Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/my-first-speech-meet-magento-2017-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/my-first-speech-meet-magento-2017-sweden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nordic Web Team organised Meet Magento 2017 Sweden for the second time, in Stockholm. The event toked place in Münchenbryggeriet (or the “Brewery Conference Center”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being in the panel moderator a year ago, this time I had the pleasure to talk on my first public presentation, which Nexcess described it being &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;a particularly interesting talk about Kubernetes and Magento 2&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insides about migrating Magento 1.x to Magento 2.x</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/insides-about-migrating-magento-1-x-to-magento-2-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/insides-about-migrating-magento-1-x-to-magento-2-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrating from Magento 1.x to Magento 2.x can be seen as a long and complex process, especially when having many custom extensions. It involves the data, the extensions, the themes and all the customisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid additional issues is recommended to start first with the migration on a fresh Magento 2.x installation (using DevBox), which will bring all the settings, products, categories, cms pages, blocks, orders, url rewrites and customers. If it starts with the design, the changes (pages and settings) will be overwritten by the official data migration tool and might cost some time to add them back. Changes made during theme design might enter in conflict with the migration tool (for example creating new attributes, which will be time consuming to debug).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First impression about Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/first-impression-about-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/first-impression-about-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With some experience on docker-compose, Kubernetes seems very stable, quick and reliable solution for the need of pushing a Magento 2.x project into the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also alternatives such as docker swarm (which has a more gengle learning curve when having docker-compose background). Willing to test multiple solutions, Kubernetes does not disappoint when doing the translation from local project into the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak peak intreaba.net (#RoR, #elasticsearch)</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/sneak-peak-intreaba-net-ror-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/sneak-peak-intreaba-net-ror-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new simplified way of adding a question and getting answers. First project will be launch only in romanian and will be build with #RoR, will have facebook authentification, #elasticsearch autocomplete, #bootstrap responsive theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access docker application by hostname</title>
      <link>https://www.avramescu.net/access-docker-application-by-hostname/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.avramescu.net/access-docker-application-by-hostname/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To access a docker application by a particular hostname, the file: &lt;code&gt;/var/lib/docker/containers/CONTAINER_ID/config.json&lt;/code&gt; requires the change of the Hostname and Domainname  &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Config&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;Hostname&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;www&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Domainname&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;example.local&amp;quot;, ...}&lt;/code&gt;. This way, the container will have all the necesarry information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
